how can I get rid of attention to be
free from well the first step is to stop
stop using them for again pleasure so
you have to refrain from obtaining
pleasure through things you're attached
to because attachment is inseparable
from the notion of being Pleasant
whatever it is if it's your house if
it's your spouse your children your
friends attachment to them means to that
degree there is a degree of pleasure in
them in the company in the presence what
they can do for you or make you provide
you provide you with and so on so you
have to basically stop maintaining that
attachment through constantly exhibiting
the behavior of of of that of gaining
pleasure through them and then start
seeing the opposite that it's actually
not pleasant but dangerous to be
attached yeah because if you start all
you have to do like saying then you
attach your house all you have to do is
that pondering thinking on the quite a
real possibility of losing it like
through natural catastrophes or anything
basic two things can happen
there are beyond your control they can
happen at any time to you and then you
realize that your whole world of
dependence upon those things are that's
where the attachment is it's going to be
swept away with it and it's very
dangerous so when you recognize that
perilous situation you are right there
in it you will you will work you will
want to be not attached to those things
and that's a first step
really
you throw those things away no see
destroying those things does not free
from attachment events because the
attachment is not a thing it's your
attitude in regard to them yeah it's it
is the most natural response then like
well I'm attached to this I'll throw it
away I'll break it apart I'll say no to
it but it doesn't affect your mind your
attitude of attachment which means
another thing will slot in instead of it
sooner or later you're gonna give in
so in order to free yourself from
attachment you need to basically discern
the reasons for attachment and things
are not the reasons they're the objects
of your attachment the reasons is what
fear for your life
feel free safety fear for your health
fear of boredom fear I'm not having
anything to do fear of loneliness all
those things that people are afraid of
and that's where they attach to other
people and to other things so that's
what you want to overcome those fears
and not act out of those fears and the
very first step of overcoming any fear
is being aware of it admitting it
discerning
free from the touch no no no no a person
can be theoretically can be living in a
very nice house a very comfortable life
have had lots of luxuries but internally
generally not be attached to it but it's
highly unlikely today that will be the
case because it takes a lot of effort
and if a person is able to make their
effort and gain their wisdom they
wouldn't be investing all that time in
maintaining all those those those things
and luxuries probably giving it up
naturally not as a responsive or I'm
bound by this um I'm sort of trapped by
my attachment soldiers destroyed the
object of it and pretend I'm not
attached no they would be overcoming it
through proper understanding they will
be removing the actual attachments not
effective things so then if something
were to happen to those things they will
suffer accountable but it doesn't mean
they seek out the destruction of those
things beforehand in order to prove
themselves that they're not if you need
to prove to yourself that you're
attached means you don't know so if you
need to prove to yourself that you're
not attached means you don't know that
you're not attached means you're
doubting it means you are attached
you're not free from that you can't say
you're free so outwardly you it's not a
measure of attachment I present care of
a big family many children but not
actually be attached to them if he has
wisdom so he'll be helping them being
there for them but if something happens
he won't be distraught and completely
completely kind of unable to continue
his life